in this content
在此内容中
we will look at the stealth technology of the f-35
我们来看看f-35的隐形技术
the radar absorbing material behind it and
它后面的雷达吸收材料和
its platformed alignment and engineering
它的平台化对齐和工程
we will try to explain the basic differences
我们将尝试解释基本差异
between the f thirty five a b and c
在f三十五a b和c之间
examining the engineering of STOVL or
检查STOVL或
short takeoff vertical landing
短距起飞垂直着陆
and the engine powering it
以及为其提供动力的发动机
and how it works in simple animation
以及它在简单动画中的工作原理
as a fifth generation fighter jet
作为第五代战斗机
we have to look at the weapon system
我们得看看武器系统
as well as the electronic warfare suite
以及电子战套件
and last but not the least the four hundred
最后但并非最不重要的四百
thousand dollar helmet and its features  now
千元头盔及其功能现在
leaving politics aside
抛开政治不谈
let's get straight to the content
让我们直接进入内容
this is the Lockheed Martin f thirty five Lightning II
这是洛克希德马丁f 35闪电II
the search for a stealth fighter that can take off
寻找可以起飞的隐形战斗机
and land in tight confines has lasted decades
狭小地带的土地已经持续了几十年
Lockheed Martin began developing experimental vertical
洛克希德·马丁公司开始开发实验垂直
rising fighters as early as nineteen fifty four
早在1954年崛起的战士
the harrier was one such aircraft that
猎鹰就是这样一种飞机
had achieved this engineering feat
完成了这项工程壮举
its technology was ahead of its time
它的技术领先于时代
but it has its flaws like every engineering marvel
但它也有缺陷就像每个工程奇迹一样
during vertical landing
垂直着陆时
it would turn over multiple times due to
它会翻转多次，因为
turbulence from its own downwash
来自自身下沉的湍流
on the tip of each wing included a small roll control
在每个机翼的尖端都包括一个小滚动控制
nozzle which had to be controlled manually by the pilot
必须由飞行员手动控制的喷嘴
to stabilize the aircraft for safe landing
稳定飞机以确保安全着陆
however
然而
the f-35b short takeoff and vertical landing system  stovl
35b短距起降系统
was an improvement
是一种进步
combining vertical landing with
垂直着陆与
long range supersonic speed
远程超音速
resulting in a stealthy
导致一个隐形的
lightning fast fighter capable of carrying modern weaponry
能够携带现代武器的闪电般的战斗机
let us look at the variants of the f
让我们看看f的变体
thirty five along with their differences
三十五以及他们的差异
there are three variants
有三种变体
all of which are single seat jets
都是单座飞机
the f thirty five a which is a conventional takeoff
f 35 a是常规起飞
and landing variant was designed for use by the United States
着陆变体是为美国设计的
air force and numerous allied nations
空军和许多盟国
this aircraft was designed to operate from
这架飞机的设计是从
standard air strips and is the sole f thirty five
标准空气条，是35号的唯一产品。
with a twenty five millimeter internal cannon
用25毫米口径的内加农炮
allowing it to replace the f sixteen multirole fighter and
允许它取代f 16多用途战斗机和
the flying cannon a ten Thunderbolt II among other aircraft
在其他飞机中，飞行大炮是十个Thunderbolt II
this cannon is not available on the other variants
这种大炮在其他变体上不可用
the f 35 b was developed specifically for short
f35 b是专门为
takeoff and vertical landing operations
起降作业
and was built to meet the
并被建造以满足
requirements of the us marine corps
美国海军陆战队的要求
the f-35b's takeoff and landing capabilities allows
35b的起飞和降落能力
marines to operate these jets from short runways or
海军陆战队从短跑道或
off the decks of amphibious assault ships while still
离开两栖攻击舰的甲板
being able to operate from standard runways
能够在标准跑道上运行
it has more robust landing gear to help
它有更坚固的起落架来帮助
with difficult carrier landings
航母着陆困难
and it has a greater internal fuel supply
它有更大的内部燃料供应
nine thousand seventy two liters
九千七十二升
to support longer range missions
支持远程任务
this variant has the added
此变体添加了
mechanical feature of foldable wings
可折叠机翼的力学特性
which makes it easier to store in ship holds
这使得储存在船舱更容易
for now  we will look at the f-35b and its specifications
现在我们来看看35b及其规格
the f-35b has a length of fifty one point two
35b有五十一点二的长度
feet and a height of fourteen point three feet
英尺高十四点三尺
a wingspan of thirty five feet
翼展三十五英尺
which helps to maneuver the plane
这有助于操纵飞机
in a planned formed alignment
按计划排列
the jet has an empty weight of fourteen
喷气式飞机的空重是14磅
thousand seven hundred twenty nine kilogram
一千七百二十九公斤
which is equivalent to the weight of seventeen jeeps
相当于十七辆吉普车的重量
it has a weapons payload of six
它的武器有效载荷为6
thousand eight hundred kilogram
一千八百公斤
which we will talk about it in more details later
我们稍后会更详细地讨论它
now that we have seen the dimensions
现在我们已经看到了维度
let us look at the basic parts of the fighter jet
让我们看看战斗机的基本部件
this is the nose of the f thirty five
这是f 35的鼻子
and inside it is a northrop grumman an apg
里面是诺斯罗普·格鲁曼和apg
eighty one active electronically
八十一个电子激活
scanned array fire control Radar
扫描阵列火控雷达
which is the world's most modern and capable Radar
这是世界上最现代化和最有能力的雷达
and serves as the backbone of the f thirty
并且是F30的中坚力量
five Lightning II's advanced Sensor suite
五闪电II的高级传感器套件
moving back
回迁
we have the canopy
我们有天篷
which has been plated with an indium tin
上面镀着铟锡
oxide layer to give it a golden sheen
氧化层赋予它金色的光泽
this helps to keep it stealthy
这有助于保持隐形
this is the lift fan doors of the f thirty five
这是f 35的升降风扇门
inside it is a rolls Royce lift system that offers a
里面是劳斯莱斯电梯系统，提供
STOVL short takeoff and vertical landing aircraft
STOVL短距起飞和垂直着陆飞机
that is exceptionally durable and dependable
非常耐用和可靠
the rolls Royce lift fan is the heart of the
劳斯莱斯升降风扇是
f 35b's thrust vectoring capability
f35b的推力矢量能力
twenty nine thousand shaft
两万九千轴
horsepower is delivered to the lift fan
马力输送到升降风扇
the exhaust nozzle
排气喷嘴
which is connected to the main engine by a drive shaft
通过传动轴连接到主机
produces a downward flowing column of
产生向下流动的柱
air at the front of the plane
飞机前部的空气
at the back
在后面
the exhaust nozzle twists
排气嘴扭动
aiming its push toward the ground for directional control
瞄准地面进行定向控制
all of this is possible because of the Pratt and
这一切都是可能的，因为普拉特和
Whitney f one three five afterburning turbo fan engine
惠特尼f一三五加力涡轮风扇发动机
it comes in two versions a conventional takeoff and landing
它有两个版本，一个传统的起飞和着陆
c tall type used in the f thirty five a and f thirty five c
c高型用于f三十五a和f三十五c
and a two cycle short takeoff vertical landing stovall model
和一个两周期短距起飞垂直着陆炉灶模型
with a forward lift fan used in the f thirty five b
f 35 b中使用的前升力风扇
let's look at how this works
让我们看看这是如何工作的
air is sucked from both the rectangular intake Ramp
空气从矩形进气坡道吸入
and fuel is sprayed into a segment of the jet pipe
燃料被喷到喷射管的一部分
where it mixes with the exhaust gas and ignites
它与废气混合并点燃
resulting in a second stage of combustion
导致第二阶段的燃烧
in order to save jet fuel during takeoff  altitude
为了在起飞高度节省喷气燃料
ascent or battle maneuvers
上升或战斗演习
the afterburner is only employed in short bursts
加力燃烧室只在短时间内使用
the exhaust nozzle is made up of petals and is designed
排气喷嘴由花瓣组成，设计
to narrow or enlarge the distance between them
缩小或扩大它们之间的距离
this is done to lessen the strain on the turbofan
这样做是为了减轻涡扇的压力
engines when they are in full afterburning mode
发动机处于完全加力模式时
all that power is being fed by the massive
所有的能量都是由巨大的
number of seven to ten internal fuel tanks
七到十个内部燃料箱的数量
let us look at where they are placed
让我们看看它们被放置在哪里
fuel tank number one is located just behind the pilot seat
一号油箱就在驾驶座后面
this is the fuel tank number two
这是二号油箱
also known as center fuselage
也称为中心机身
this is fuel tank number three
这是三号油箱
also known as engine feed tank
也称为发动机进料罐
moving back we have wing carry through which fuel tank
往后移动，我们有机翼，通过哪个油箱。
number four along with two fuselage vent tanks
四号和两个机身排气箱
on the wings are two massive fuel tanks on each side
机翼两侧各有两个巨大的燃料箱
also known as the wing fuel tank
也被称为机翼油箱
two more vertical fin vent tanks are
还有两个垂直翅片排气罐是
located on the fins of the aircraft
位于飞机的尾翼上
now let us look at the parts of the wing
现在让我们看看翅膀的各个部分
two rudders are located just above the tail fuselage
两个方向舵位于尾部机身正上方
the two massive elevators are located further down
两部大型电梯位于更远的地方
the lifting force can be decreased and appropriately
提升力可适当减小
increased since the ailerons have the ability to move up and
因为副翼有能力向上移动
down while the rudders assist in moving the plane left or
当方向舵帮助飞机向左移动时下降
right
对吧
this is the elevators
这是电梯
which may be modified to make the aircraft move up or down
可以修改以使飞机向上或向下移动
check out our last video on how the wings work
看看我们最后一个关于翅膀如何工作的视频
with the control surface in a very basic
与控制表面在一个非常基本的
explanation the fa eighteen super hornet
解释fa十八超级大黄蜂
as the name suggests stealth fighter
顾名思义隐形战机
let us look at how it was able to avoid most of the radar
让我们看看它是如何避开大部分雷达的
believe it or not
信不信由你
the shaping of the f thirty five
f三十五的塑造
provides most of its stealth technology
提供了大部分的隐形技术
this is known as planform alignment
这就是所谓的平面排列
this improved flight design orients key
这种改进的飞行设计定向关键
flight surfaces at the same angle
飞行面角度相同
as a result radar energy is scattered away
结果雷达能量被分散
from the plane rather than diffusing it
从飞机上而不是扩散它
where it could still potentially be detected
它仍然有可能被检测到
this planform aligned has to be built from the ground up
这个排列的平台必须从头开始建造
the Radar paint technology is still classified
雷达喷漆技术仍属机密
but this is what we know from aviation experts
但这是我们从航空专家那里得知的
and what we learned is they used
我们了解到的是他们使用
a Radar absorbing material
一种雷达吸收材料
RAM is a type of Polymer based material that is put to
RAM是一种基于聚合物的材料，可用于
the surface of stealth military aircraft like the f
像f这样的隐形军用飞机的表面
twenty two Raptor and f thirty five Lightning II
22猛禽和f 35闪电II
this reduce Radar cross section and thus
这减少了雷达横截面，因此
making them more difficult to detect by Radar
使它们更难被雷达探测到
stealth with low visibility
低能见度隐身
the f thirty five's aligned edges
f35的对齐边缘
decreased engine signature
减少引擎签名
internal weapon and fuel carriage
内部武器和燃料运输
and embedded sensors all
和嵌入式传感器
contribute to its exceptional stealth
有助于其卓越的隐身性
the f-35 has an unrivaled ability to elude
f-35拥有无与伦比的躲避能力
adversary detection and enter contested airspace
对手探测并进入有争议的空域
thanks to its stealth design from the start
得益于其从一开始的隐形设计
complementing the stealth technology are these hidden
作为隐形技术的补充
piece of engineering the an/asq 239 electronic suite is at
an/asq 239电子套件的工程部分位于
the heart of the f 35's electronic warfare system
f35电子战系统的核心
a modular system that provides both
提供两者的模块化系统
defensive and offensive capabilities
防御和进攻能力
ranging from the detection of hostile emitters
从探测到敌方排放物
to threat geolocation
威胁地理位置
to the automated release of countermeasures
到自动释放对策
infrared flares or radar reflecting chaff
红外线照明弹或雷达反射箔条
now let us look at the weapons capability
现在让我们看看武器的能力
of the f thirty five stealth fighter
f35隐形战斗机
this is the electro optical targeting system
这是光电瞄准系统
this improves situational awareness for f thirty five pilots
这提高了f 35飞行员的态势感知能力
and enables aircrews to identify points of interest
并使机组人员能够识别兴趣点
conduct reconnaissance
进行侦察
and precisely launch laser and gps guided munitions
并精确发射激光和gps制导弹药
it is the first sensor to integrate forward looking
它是第一个集成前瞻性的传感器
infrared and infrared search and track functions
红外和红外搜索和跟踪功能
the f thirty five carries weaponry internally in
f35在内部携带武器
stealth mode or externally in a permissive
隐身模式或外部处于允许状态
environment in a situation where they don't expect to
环境在他们不期望的情况下
have any threats to their safety from hostile forces
他们的安全受到敌对势力的威胁
externally
外部地
the jassm will be carried by all variants of the f-35
jassm将由f-35的所有变体携带
enhancing reach
扩大覆盖面
lethality and survivability against
杀伤力和生存力
heavily defended strategic targets
重兵防守的战略目标
and increasing the ability to deter near peer adversaries
并增加威慑附近对手的能力
l洛克希德马丁创造了AGM 158 JASSM
l洛克希德马丁创造了 AGM 158 JASSM
joint air to surface stand off missile
联合空对地待命导弹
a low observable stand off air launched
发射了一个可观察到的低空待命
cruise missile for the American armed forces
美国军队的巡航导弹
it is a substantial
这是一个实质性的
covert long range weapon with an Armor piercing warhead
带有穿甲弹头的隐蔽远程武器
weighing four hundred fifty kilograms or one thousand pounds
重四百五十公斤或一千磅
the aim one hundred twenty Amraam can
目标是一百二十Amraam可以
be carried by the inboard station  flares
由内站照明弹携带
chaff and tow decoys are stored in two
箔条和拖曳诱饵被储存在两个
compartments behind the Armament Bays
武器舱后面的隔间
the f thirty five features two internal weapons bays with
f35有两个内部武器舱
four weapon stations to maintain its stealth shape
四个武器站以保持其隐身状态
the two outboard weapon stations can each carry
两个舷外武器站可以各自携带
two thousand five hundred pound of ordnance
两千五百磅的军械
or one thousand five hundred pound for the f thirty five b
或者一千五百英镑买f三十五b
while the two inboard weapon stations
而机舱内的两个武器站
can carry air to air missiles
可以携带空对空导弹
the joint direct attack munition  JDAM
联合直接攻击弹药JDAM
Paveway series of bombs
铺路系列炸弹
joint standoff weapon  jsow
联合对峙武器jsow
and cluster munitions are all air to
集束弹药都是空运到
surface weaponry for the outboard station
舷外空间站的水面武器
now let us look at the four hundred thousand dollar helmet
现在让我们看看价值四十万美元的头盔
this is the helmet mounted display which gives the pilot
这是头盔显示器，它给飞行员
critical flight information and sent directly to the visors
重要的飞行信息并直接发送到护目镜
this is the integrated digital night vision device
这是集成数字夜视仪
the helmet is fed with data feed
头盔有数据馈送
which displays imagery from a set of six
它显示一组六个的图像
cameras mounted on the f thirty five airframe
安装在f35机身上的摄像机
which moves along with the head of the pilot
它随着飞行员的头部移动
the helmet also provides information about target identity
头盔还提供目标身份信息
and distance and even recommends which weapon to use
和距离，甚至建议使用哪种武器
so when looking through the plane
所以当透过飞机看的时候
if the pilot sees something that
如果飞行员看到什么
should be hit by a missile
应该被导弹击中
or just wants a closer look
或者只是想仔细看看
all he has to do is look at it to lock on
他所要做的就是看着它锁定
then flip a switch to zoom in
然后翻转开关放大
the pilot can therefore see straight through their own
飞行员因此可以直接看穿他们自己
body and the floor of the plane to the terrain below
机身和飞机地板到下面的地形
do support your small content creators
请支持您的小型内容创作者
as we bring out videos like these
当我们拿出这样的视频时
let's grow together and hit the million subscriber mark
让我们一起成长，达到百万用户大关